if you are a coach course creator you
need to grow your email list online and
growing my email list is the number one
reason why we've hit seven figures in
this business in this video I'm going to
be talking to you about the best ways to
grow your email list as well as what to
do and what not to do for those of you
that I haven't met yet I've been helping
coaches and course creators for years
over 21 years in fact scale their
businesses online I've personally built
multiple businesses in this industry to
over $10 million a year and I help
beginners make between to $25,000 a
month very quickly online and growing
your email list is the number one
activity that you need to do if you are
a course creator or coach online here's
why even though we say we're going to we
use social media to grow our business
that's not really the most accurate
representation because our email list is
really the number one thing that helps
us grow and when I started this business
I had built other businesses that I had
helped other Founders grow and scale um
and we were growing the email list the
whole time with those businesses for
some reason I overlooked the fact of
doing the email list in my own business
I thought that content creation was all
that I needed to do and put value out
there and tell people about the value
that I have to offer as far as that goes
how many of youall have heard put value
out there be a giver and people will
come back and they'll buy from you
that's not really the case okay it is
the case but it's not really the case
what you have to do is you have the
value right here this is the value that
you're going to offer people and and you
might be watching this video saying wait
a sec Jeremiah you're giving me value on
a video right here what I'm not on your
email list let me
explain this isn't a sales video and I'm
not expecting you to buy anything from
me from from this video this is more of
an exposure method um I have a coaching
program you can go find on my website
where I work with people just like you
to scale their businesses but what you
need to do is you need to have offers
where you deliver the value
behind an email for and how do yall get
sick and tired of seeing people that
they're like oh put in your email
address and you can get this information
if you're sick and tired of that then
you're not going to be able to grow your
business because you're judging the very
activity that is actually the most
important aspect of creating any kind of
significant income which is finances
coming into your business which is
growing an email list and so you can't
judge negatively the activity that is
the single most powerful activity for
you growing your business and number two
is selling learning how to sell because
once you get people on your email list
and then you deliver value we need to
then close a sale I meet way too many
coaches and course creators out there
they're like well I'm just going to give
value and then if people like it they're
going to come back and they're going to
they're going to want to do business
with me that's a romantic
facade that does not exist in reality
with anybody that's out there and so for
you to be able to actually scale your
business for you to actually grow things
you have to get people onto an email
list and make offers to them that are
very specific that are intentional that
are not
passive to get people to take action
with you and this is one of the number
one areas when I work with my clients I
walk them through a multi-step process
that the ones who succeed do
this and without exception the ones who
struggle are still not quite sure yet
what they're going to use to grow their
email list why are they not quite sure
yet well that's what I'm going to be
addressing here in this video and that's
one of the number one keys that you want
to be able to watch out for when it
comes to Growing your email list is in
decision the action of indecision is one
of the biggest things that stops us from
being able to be successful because we
have not decided yet what we're going to
put out there and often it's because of
either fear worry doubt something
internally where we feel like maybe it's
not good enough yet maybe we're not
ready yet to put this out there and I
and I meet a lot of exceptional coaches
every single week that I work with I I
work with hundreds of coaches in my
coaching program in fact and they tell
me Jeremiah I just am not sure if this
is going to
work now why are they not sure it's
going to work because they don't have
the conviction or the belief
that the idea that they have to put out
there to grow their email list is what's
going to get people to buy into it and
many times they come to me looking to
give them conviction and and and and
I'll I'll be honest with you I don't I
don't do
codependency it's one of those things
that actually determines if somebody's a
good client of mine or not is is I will
refuse to be codependent with them to
where I'm the one deciding for them what
they need to do what I will do is I will
give them a framework on how to make the
decision for themselves so that it comes
from them so that they're not making me
now the responsible party in their own
business growth okay and that's one of
the number one things if you are a coach
or a mentor do not get into codependency
with your clients it's an topic for
another time as far as that goes but it
will absolutely ruin your credibility
your ability to actually grow a business
you'll be frustrated and disappointed if
you're constantly in the weeds with
codependency with people now let's go
back to the email list you got to make a
decision as to what you are going to
make an offer
around knowing what you're going to
offer People starts with who do you help
what problem do you solve and what is
the value that you're going to be
delivering to people and you got to pick
something one of the problems that I
meet with a lot of people is that they
have as many ideas as there are stars in
the sky okay there's a lot of stars in
the sky right and they have as many
ideas as there are stars stars in the
sky and they can't pick which one they
want to do they're afraid of one of them
not working out or one of them not
coming together for them the way that
they want it to or expect it to and so
what I have to tell people is you have
to learn to make a decision even if you
don't have total
certainty and be okay with it maybe not
being the best decision we go through
our lives believing that we're going to
make the best decision all the time and
that that's always going to be that we
should never make a decision unless it's
the best decision can I tell you this
that's
subjective that's biased the best
decision can change Tomorrow based on
new parameters as far as that goes and
as you grow your business as you decide
in your Niche what we have to do is we
have to learn how to become decisive
even if there might be a potentially
better idea the next
day and so even when I make videos like
this there's a a thousand and one ideas
that I can make for a video but if I sat
there and ruminated on well I don't know
which one's the right idea to make I
would literally never make any video
content I would never put anything out
there I would never make any offers and
my business would be at zero because of
that and that's where I see a lot of
coaches that are watching my content is
that their business is at zero because
of the indecision bug because they're
afraid of it being the wrong idea
because they're afraid of it not working
out for them how they want it to work
out and so number one make a decision
and deal with that thing inside of you
that fear of missing out start to
regulate your own emotions in a way to
where you're not as anxious about it
needing to be perfect before you move
forward okay find peace inside of you
not because you made the best decision
that's a that's a piece of advice that I
think will help a lot of people is if
you actually find your inner peace not
because you know that this is the best
decision
but because you're like it's a decision
that's as close as possible and it's the
best one that keeps coming up and you
actually tap into your even your
intuition and start listening to your
inner voice you can start to move
forward in the right direction to make
the right decision so now once we've
decided on what we're going to offer
right I I I have a couple of different
offers that I put out there to grow my
email list we're going to look at what
is the Avenue that we want to grow our
email list with so there's a couple of
different Avenues you can do a free
ebook you could do a live event you
could do a mini class and these are
really the three main ways that most
people grow their email list is they
either have a mini class that people can
sign up for they have a live event that
they're going to be hosting like a
webinar or a challenge or they have an
ebook offer or a checklist or some kind
of a of a handout that they're going to
be giving people okay and so pick one of
those three I will tell you the one that
actually sells the most is still
generally going to be the mini class SL
live event and Live Events actually have
a little bit of a of an edge on this
still because you get people into a
captive environment where they're
watching you specifically and you can
automate your Live Events as well to
make it to where you don't have to
necessarily show up live and in person
to use your time by creating an
evergreen type of a funnel or an offer
as far as that goes and this is really
the best way to do that and so if we
look at it the very best ways to grow
your email list is by delivering some
kind of video
content excuse me that people can sign
up for with their email address you
might be watching this right now saying
well why can't I just put it on YouTube
sure you can but the chances of it
actually turning into sales for you is
very low because when it comes to
YouTube content when it comes to just
content that you're just putting out
there into The Ether there's no
direction there's no specificity there's
no real moment where people are are
directed in that way the algorithm might
show your content to people but until
people are on your email
list they've not made a commitment with
you and it's very passive and they're
not really in your
ecosystem and so there's the activity of
getting people to put in their email
address that actually psychologically
triggers something in people's minds to
pay attention to the rest of the things
that you put out there okay and so
understand that even if it seems silly
to get them on your email list because
maybe you're not getting all your sales
off your email list the activity of them
taking action by giving you their
information that physical activity of
clicking on a page typing in their name
and email address triggers something in
their minds that I don't see changing
anytime soon that they are more
committed to what you have to offer and
if they exchange finances at the end of
that one of the ways that we see that
people will do this they'll grow their
email list and they might have a an
upsell offer as low as a dollar even
we've done before where people will just
let's pay a dollar for a bonus upgrade
on top of this maybe you put an ebook
out there and then you have a bonus
upgrade for a dollar that's another
great funnel that I've seen a lot of
people doo don't just put the ebook out
there have an upgrade at the end of it
that might have three lessons of a video
course now we're cooking with gasoline
and this is the right way to do things
when it comes to Growing your email list
is you're delivering value to
people and maybe your brain is thinking
right now I don't know what I could put
into a new book I don't know what I
could say for three lessons in a free
course I don't know what would be good
enough for people to actually watch or
listen to and that's where the brain
starts deceiving us because I can tell
you in your experiences in your life
leading up to this moment in time that
you have enough information and
experience based on your Niche based on
who you help that you could create
something that is exceptionally of value
for people and one of the best ways to
know what to deliver to people is what I
call
feedback
looping what you want to do is you want
to take the feedback from other people
of the questions they are asking you and
loop it right back into what you're
delivering to people now you might say
well Jeremiah I don't have any feedback
from people that's not a problem we live
in an incredible day and age in 2024
where you can Sim at the feedback from
people using artificial
intelligence so we can use chat GPT to
dialogue and come up with a few great
ideas that can help help lead us to make
a decision to what a great lead Magnet
or email list offer would be and that's
one of the phrases when it comes to
Growing your email list that we use is
called a
lead magnet so a lead magnet is
something that you put out out there
that people sign up for with their name
and email address that gets their email
address and you also now we put their
phone number in there as well so we can
even send some text messages back to
people and then from there we have
captured their
information by capturing their
information now we have a number of
different things that we can do we've
qualified them the algorithms on social
media put them into a special bucket
that we can now retarget to them and
this allows us to even train our
algorithm them when we're marketing or
promoting to show more of our content to
people that are more likely to fit into
a certain bucket of people that are more
likely to
be more people that are going to grow
our email list so the idea is this
becomes an echo chamber in a positive
way you know we hear about Echo chamers
being a negative thing when in fact when
it comes to marketing you want to create
an echo chamber effect and the reason
why is because now your efforts go 10
times further by them being Target tared
towards a very specific group of people
that are all dealing with the same
problems that are all struggling with
the same issues and there's a resonant
frequency literally that ends up
happening similar like when you strum a
guitar there's a resonance inside of
that chamber of the guitar that creates
that audible sound that's the same thing
that happens when we end up creating a a
a lead magnet that connects with people
in an effective way it creates this
feedback loop whoo whoa whoa whoa W wo
there's an audible sound but it's
actually a more of a mental frequency
resonance you don't need to understand
the Neuroscience or the scientific
Factor behind that for it to work for
you so what you want to look for is you
want to look for what is the
pattern of the most common struggle pain
and frustration that people have now we
don't lead with the pain and frustration
but then what is the desire that people
have to move away from that pain and
frustration so there's a desire that
draws people in that they really really
want that they really really desire and
so then when you can encapsulate that
and bottle it up like bottled lightning
there's a book right here on my shelf
that I've been reading called The Power
of moments uh by chip and Dan Heath
right here it's a really great book um
but this Photograph on it is really what
I what I see is the an image of an
effective lead magnet is we bottle up
the moment where people have an epiphany
the moment where people start to make a
decision the moment where trust is built
with people and Trust really is what
you're trying to build up trust is the
currency of your business your ability
to be able to make the kind of finances
that you want to make in your business
is directly correlated to your ability
to build trust with people
effectively and so the way that you
build trust is you create that Echo
chamber people trust other people that
sound like them that speak like them
that talk about the things that they
care about that show that they
understand their frustrations and so one
of the mistakes that I see that a lot of
coaches and mentors make it makes me
very sad because they could be making
millions of dollars but instead their
ego starts deceiving them is they care
about well I want to deliver this
content to people or this is what I want
to put out to people or this is what I
really want to help people with or this
is really what I want to tell people or
or the one of the worst ones well this
doesn't sound like me I wouldn't say it
that way
and I'm not talking about you being
inauthentic but I'm talking about you
figuring out what is the language
pattern of the people that you're trying
to reach and then merge that with what
you have to offer to people individually
and
uniquely and then you bring that to the
table as something that people can sign
up for on a lead magnet with their email
address you're going to deliver value in
the form of a video
training of some kind whether it be
delivered live or
pre-recorded and then you're going to
get people to sign up for that so once
you have your lead magnet now we go into
what I call the promotion stage okay so
the promotion stage is we have our lead
magnet right here this is our lead
magnet and we start promoting it on
social media we might even be on
podcasts we might be on other people's
email it's like affiliate marketing you
might even post it on your website
blogging you might do it on YouTube
which by the way YouTube really is a
social network it's just a different
form of a social network okay so all of
these are ways that we can promote our
lead magnet to People by explicitly
telling people about what we have to
offer you know listen if you're a coach
or mentor and and and you're watching my
content I work with people every single
week and my client growth accelerator to
help them be able to create their lead
magnets and to be able to use social
media to grow their businesses I'd love
to work with you as well you can find
the link below to be able to do that
right there what I just said and by the
way it was seemed like a little bit of
commercial right well it was intentional
because I was saying and directly
talking about a solution that I offer
people that helps people to build their
business as far as that goes and as we
start to develop different lead magnets
and things like that I start to mention
what those are currently you know I have
a free chat GPT document on my website
that you can use you can go grab it over
at Jeremiah Kowski decom that has all of
my best chat GPT prompts on it so that's
a PDF it's a one pager right there now
if anybody grabs that I can actually
deliver to them additional
information based around those that sign
up for that to give them access ACC to
other trainings or other lead magnets or
things like that that I have to offer
okay and so from here what we do is
based on our email list based on that
connection that we're making with people
based on driving that
connection we're able to get people to
to step into what we call a
buying decision-making
process to where we're able to make a
presentation to to them of what we have
to offer okay and so without you making
an explicit presentation to people how
do you expect people to buy from you
well there's so much value and they're
just either going to tell their friends
or they're going to go look for it and
then they're going to go sign
up sounds romantic doesn't work in
reality so you got to be intentional to
create moments of opportunity where you
get to present your product what you
have to sell to people people in a very
intentional
way and generally we don't do that
through our social media we don't
explicitly sell to people even through
something like YouTube videos like this
now I might mention to you what I have
to offer I might mention to you my
coaching program but I'm not selling it
to you I'm just mentioning it as far as
that goes that you know that I have that
that I offer to people okay because the
place that I do sell to people
happens once people are on my email list
as far as that goes and then you might
say well I don't want to just send I
just don't want to I don't want to send
salesy messages to people on my email
like there's so many okay listen can I
can I level with you there are so many
excuses that people come up with why
they're not going to do what I just
talked about in this
video and that's why they're not making
money because they've come up with
reasons why to talk themselves out of
the very activity that's going to make
them the most amount of money because of
what people think about them because of
how they don't want to look because of
how they don't want to be perceived and
all these different
things when in fact just growing your
email list is the most effective
activity bar none compared to anything
else you do that's going to be able to
create the kind of income that you want
to create and so what we want to do is
we want to look at what is that solution
that we can offer to people let's pick
some form of a medium let's build out
a landing page an offer something that
can deliver to people the value maybe
it's going to be on a zoom call maybe
it's going to be a a you a YouTube video
that's private that we're going to send
to them you can keep it simple or as
advanced as you want I see people way
over complicate this process you can
literally
upload a private YouTube video that
nobody else has access to and send that
to somebody in in in an email link and
now you have a now you have a lead
magnet that delivers value to people
doesn't have to be over complicated
doesn't have to have all these features
and things like that doesn't have to
have all this stuff but if there's at
least some way where you can make a
connection with somebody and then you
can make a presentation to them of what
it is that you have for sale what it is
that you offer to people and how you
help them that will allow you to go from
where you are to be able to scale your
business and to be able to get more
people onto it so when we can learn now
we have the lead
magnet now we can start to put together
pieces of content to put onto these
different platforms from here one of the
biggest mistakes people make is that
they're trying to make all this content
organically to grow their
business when in fact that's not what
grows their business it's creating all
this
content creating all this content leads
people to the lead magnet that then
grows their email list and anybody who
is successful in the coaching or online
course creation space does that because
that is the most effective process to be
able to scale and increase the results
that you want in your business and
that's what I work with people with
every single week in my coaching program
is developing out their lead magnets
coming up with their advertising
campaigns their social media content how
do they deliver their presentations how
do we optimize their product how do we
make sure that they have something
that's incredibly of value to deliver
and get people results we have clients
that are making tens of thousands of
dollars every single month we have
clients that are making millions of
dollars every single month as well and
everywhere in between so again if you
would like to work with me if you'd like
to come into my space and and have me
personally help you build your business
I'd love to do so you can get on the
waiting list for my my accelerator
program you can check out some of the
live events that we have to offer when
we when we have those that are coming up
and you can go through additional
trainings that we have subscribe to this
YouTube channel to stay up to speed as
to what are the best ways to scale and
build your business you don't want to
get stuck in the content creation
hamster wheel which is where you don't
actually have an offer or a lead magnet
to send people to and that's one of the
biggest mistakes people make they're
making all this content to get followers
and to build an audience and it's like
for what you create the content after
you have the lead magnet and then you're
able to send people to what you have to
offer to sell and one of the other
things that you want to do is you don't
have to create your offer that you had
to sell up front you can actually
pre-sell something to people you can get
people in front of you have a a waiting
list or a starting time and this is one
of the most effective ways to be able to
build in the scale of business is you
don't have to have the whole thing done
or built before you put it out there to
people you can have people join you and
jump in and then when you open the doors
to it you'll have a flood of people that
have been itching and waiting to join
you that's another great effective way
to build urgency and build Authority in
your business that people buy from you a
lot of people they're like they're so
desperate to get sales desperation leads
to zero sales but when you can learn how
to effectively move people along a path
that creates the right buying triggers
in their minds and you can do so with
excellence in a way that's not difficult
that's simple that that is sustainable
for your lifestyle you can have a
sustain aable business while only having
to work 5 to 10 hours a week that makes
you multiple six and even seven figures
and I'd love to help you do so stay
plugged in love to see you on my
accelerator program and we'll talk soon
have a good one